GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
The infected are being
killed all over the city.
RA'S: I'm the one you seek.
I am Ra's al Ghul.
This man is your past...
Now, embrace your future.
(YELLING)
RA'S: Use the waters, Bruce.
(COUGHS)
PENGUIN: You were the
one time I let love weaken me.
I want you around
as a constant reminder
to never make
that mistake again.
(SCREAMS)
I heard about Alfred.
Is he gonna be okay?
You don't give a damn about Alfred,
and you sure as hell don't care about me.
I know you better than that.
I thought you did.
GORDON: Jonathan
Crane's father made a toxin
from the adrenal
glands of his victims
while they experienced terror.
(SCREAMING)
- What do you want?
- I'm tired of just surviving.
I want more.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
I'm sorry, Alfred.
I've been trying to find
who I am for so long.
Who am I supposed to be?
Money! Now!
ALFRED: You need
to find your true north
and let that guide you.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Money! Now!
(WOMAN EXCLAIMS)
Hurry up. All of it!
Give me the ring.
BRUCE: You have
one chance. Walk away.
Who's this?
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
License. I got a license.
(SINGING) Never
gonna give you up
Never gonna let you down
Never gonna run
around and desert you
Never gonna make you cry
Never gonna say goodbye
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD GASPING)
Nobody move!
Jewelry, watches, wallets!
MAN: You know
the drill. Let's go.
- We want it all.
- MAN: Let's go.
- Hey, you.
- Come on. Nice. Thank you.
Ah.
- Jackpot.
- Let me see that.
MAN: All the money.
(SCOFFS)
Cheapskate, huh?
(WHISTLES)
Come on.
Excuse me.
Hi.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
That's Victor Zsasz.
I know who it is.
What do you want?
Oh, I was just passing
by, heard the ruckus.
You know you can't commit
a crime in Gotham now
without a license
from Penguin, right?
Is that right?
Well, we just started it
so word's still getting out.
We ain't kicking half our
take to that little creep.
Well, that's a problem.
Maybe you ain't noticed,
but there's, uh, four of us
and only one of you.
- (CROWD GASPS)
- My finger!
(MAN GROANING)
No license, no crime.
Now, drop the loot, and blow.
You tell Penguin he
hasn't heard the last of this.
GUEST: And stay out.
(CROWD MURMURING)
I can't thank you enough.
Don't bother because,
you see, those guys...
They do have a license.
Mazel tov.
(CROWD SCREAMING)
Seriously?
Best wedding ever.
You know, we
appreciate all you've done.
Do you?
Three months ago,
following the Tetch incident,
this city was in flames.
I came to you and
offered to cut crime in half,
and I delivered.
Violent crime is down 57%.
But now you want to,
uh, literally unionize crime.
- But we can't possibly...
- Quiet!
(EXHALES)
I remember when I sat
there in the mayor's chair.
I do not envy you.
Nor you.
Commissioner of Police
in a city notorious for crime.
That's why I wanna help.
But...
We are fully aware
of all you've done.
Are you?
What do you think really happened
to those hordes of criminals
who once prowled our streets?
- I'll tell you. I hunted them down...
- No, no, no...
I made Gotham safe.
Me.
But this is Gotham City,
there will always be crime.
What I'm offering is crime
in the hands of professionals
and held to agreed-upon terms...
From which you'll profit.
God bless America.
You have a choice.
An era of calm, prosperity,
or a return to the
good old days.
And they will return
with a vengeance.
We deny everything to the press.
Mmm.
What you need to
worry about is the GCPD.
When one of your officers finds
someone committing a crime,
if that person has a
license, they walk away.
Three percent each,
uh, from the take.
Two to split between you.
- Two and a half.
- One!
- You...
- Yes, fine. Done.
Excellent.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I have to go prepare
for the grand opening
of my new club,
the Iceberg Lounge.
Good luck.
Smile, gentlemen,
it's a new day.
(DOOR CREAKS)
- Hi, Frank.
- Good morning, Jim.
I'll get your
coffee in a second.
Sure.
- Mornin'.
- Good morning.
Everything okay, Frank?
Everything's fine, copper.
I got a license.
Penguin-approved.
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
I'll take that coffee to go.
Come on, man.
Hey, what the
hell are you doing?
I got... I got a license!
Yeah, and unless you shut up,
you're also gonna get a fat lip.
We got a problem?
HARVEY: Penguin
guarantees these numbers?
PENN: Mr. Cobblepot
has negotiated them
with the Mayor and Commissioner.
These are damn good numbers.
But I already heard
from the Commissioner.
We have to play ball. What
the hell are you doing here?
Compliance with
the licenses is key.
Mr. Cobblepot worries
about Detective Gordon.
- He has a history.
- My men
will honor the licenses.
You let me worry about Gordon.
Now get the hell out of my office.
(SCOFFS)
- Who was that?
- A, uh, dung beetle.
What's up?
I pulled this off of some guy
robbing my corner bar.
You're a homicide detective.
Isn't a stick-up a little JV?
I'm a cop. I see
a crime, I stop it.
This is the second one
of these I've come across,
- and I'm not the only one.
- Yeah.
Harvey.
Harvey, we
cannot let this slide.
Word's come down
from the Commissioner,
you find someone with
one of those, they walk.
And before you get
on your high horse,
three months ago, this
city was in a tailspin.
We survived because Penguin
took control of the underworld.
I'm not giving this
city over to Penguin.
I don't care what the
Commissioner says.
What about your
fellow cops, huh?
The past month, how
many have been shot? None.
I know the stats.
Jim, we will bust Penguin
one day, I promise you.
But this city has to get
back on her feet, please?
Harvey, I get that,
but every day the citizens
of Gotham look to Penguin
and not the GCPD
to keep them safe,
the harder it's gonna
be to win them back.
You want people to trust cops,
there are better ways of doing
it than spitting in Penguin's eyes.
You see one of these,
you walk.
ALFRED: Bloody Penguin.
There must be some way
we can turn this against him.
Just stop. Stop, right there.
How does this fit
into what we're doing?
What was the initial reason
that you popped on that mask,
and you went out there?
We agreed that I have to be
ready for when Ra's al Ghul returns.
You yourself said there's no
substitute for real world encounters.
But my point is, if that is our
mission, we must hold to it.
My finger was on the
button that released the virus.
- Oh, I see.
- I know I didn't press it,
but I feel responsible
for what happened.
And more than that, I can make
a difference in Gotham, Alfred.
- I know I can.
- And that is what we call
"mission creep," Master Bruce.
You're trying to achieve
not one but two objectives.
So, go on then, which
one is your priority?
It's messy, sir.
It's dangerous.
I hear you, Alfred,
but I can prepare myself for
Ra's, and make Gotham safer.
You have to trust me.
(DOOR CLOSES)
MAN: (OVER P.A.) All
inmates, this is your last call.
In five minutes, be sure to
make your way to your door.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
This way.
Hey, Warden Reed.
Warden Reed's the boss here.
(HUMMING OFF-KEY)
(INMATE WHISTLING)
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
(SCREECHING)
- Where is he?
- This way.
(MAN GRUNTING)
Back when I was
an orderly in here,
he'd always talk about his
dad, and this formula he'd made.
Some sort of scare juice.
Made you see your greatest fear.
When we get a hold of that,
we don't got to worry
about Zsasz or Penguin,
or nobody.
What's wrong with him, anyway?
The toxin his father
injected him with
overloaded Jonathan's
fear response.
His mind created a
sort of bogeyman figure
and now it haunts him.
I find it very useful
for controlling him.
Jonathan, you're
going with these men.
- What? Wait, where are you taking me?
- Just wanna give someone a little scare.
Excellent.
(BIRD SQUAWKING)
(PANTING) Yeah,
that's all my dad's stuff.
But, look, I can't be
here after dark, please.
I really... I cannot
be here after...
You were your daddy's
little assistant, weren't you?
You helped with the experiments.
Some, but I don't
know everything.
Now you're gonna take
your daddy's notebooks,
and make as much of
that fear juice as I say.
And so you don't get lonely,
the boys here
brought you a friend.
CRANE: No.
(SCREAMS) No! Stop!
No, you don't understand! Stop!
No, you don't understand!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
May I have your
attention, please?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
All the money, now!
Give it to me! All of it!
Hey, you have a license?
(SCREAMS)
Look at me.
(ROARING)
(SIREN WAILS)
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
MAN: Fiery demons. Demons.
Fiery demons, demons.
Demons, yeah. We'll catch 'em.
- Get him out of here. Go, go, go.
- Fiery demon.
Hey.
Did Penguin issue
a license for this?
Why are you asking me?
Best of my knowledge, no.
Then why do something so public
unless you're trying to
send Penguin a message?
I hope the message was, "Please
send Victor Zsasz down here to kill me."
Because that's exactly
what's gonna happen.
- Not if I find them first.
- Hey.
You asked me to stop
busting crooks with licenses.
This gang didn't have a license.
And you're gonna
find them before Zsasz
just to prove that
GCPD still matters?
That's not thumbing
your nose at Penguin?
- Fire me.
- Hey, don't tempt me.
You got a lead?
The victims, the
way they're acting,
their terror reminds
me of Crane's formula.
You think someone's
using the fear juice?
It ain't him, he's
dead, remember,
not that that matters
much in this town anymore.
He's dead, his son isn't.
REED: Jonathan
Crane's condition is fragile.
I'm afraid he can't see anyone,
certainly not the two
men who killed his father.
Yeah, so, uh, how many
loonies you got in this joint?
Four hundred and thirty-six
total. We mustn't call them loonies.
Of course not.
(DOOR BUZZES)
How about staff that
had access to Crane?
Any of them not
show up for work?
All present and accounted for.
- You don't wanna check?
- I don't need to.
See, that's impressive,
'cause I run a precinct
and if half of my cops didn't
show up, I'd be none the wiser.
- It's true. He wouldn't.
- Clearly we have
different professional
standards.
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
Jonathan Crane's
father created a toxin
that makes people
see their greatest fear.
This morning, it was
used to rob a bank.
How is that my problem?
HARVEY: Let me
explain it to you.
See, whoever robbed the
bank, they challenged Penguin,
and all we have to do is tell
Penguin that you're involved,
and he'll send Victor Zsasz
down here to talk to you.
Jim, how would
you describe Victor?
Victor Zsasz...
A homicidal maniac and sadist.
A homicidal maniac and sadist
of the highest
professional standards.
So you can talk with us here
and now or you can talk to Victor.
They threatened
me. I had no choice.
We want a name, putz.
HARVEY: I knew it
rang a bell. Grady Harris.
Ran a crew a few years back.
Him and his cousin Merton.
Couple of cowboys
from the sticks.
Grady!
GCPD!
(GORDON GROANS)
(HARVEY GROANS)
Well, well. Look at
what we got here.
What's wrong with you pigs?
Harassing honest
fellows like us,
when there's real
criminals out there.
You robbed a bank in broad daylight.
That don't make you a criminal?
I'm an outlaw.
Outlaws have a code.
(GRUNTS)
Criminals, they'll
take everything.
They'll take a man's livelihood.
Like the Penguin
and his licenses.
But we're gonna
show him, you'll see.
Penguin wouldn't give you
a license if you begged him
till the cows came
home, you stupid hick.
You're lucky I'm not the
Penguin. He'd gut you right here.
We're better than them!
Take care.
Pigs.
(CHUCKLES)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, check it out.
MAN: Babe, lost?
Ooh.
Looking for company?
(MEN MURMURING)
She all by herself.
Just let me go, okay?
Not a chance.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
- (WHIP CRACKS)
- (MEN GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
Don't turn your back on a guy
unless you're sure he's down.
(PANTING)
Otherwise, not bad.
Does this mean we can get pizza?
(GRUNTS)
I'm just saying, you
steal my pepperoni again,
- I'll break your fingers.
- So you're saying,
do steal your pepperoni again.
I come in peace.
You ladies were not
easy to track down.
Then again, I can see
why you don't advertise.
Didn't you used to be rich?
That was before your
boss stole my club.
Well, you murdered his mom
and tried to kill him.
So, call it even?
Is there a reason you're here?
Know about these?
The boss can't have you
operating on your own.
Now, he could just kill you,
but he figures it's time to
let bygones be bygones.
How big of him.
Tomorrow night's the
opening of his club,
come by, kiss the ring,
get your license.
Is that pepperoni?
Goes without saying,
this is one of those
"or else" kinda deals.
Later.
- We got to find a new place.
- Why?
If we join Penguin, we
can at least get work.
I came to you because
I wanted to move up.
And look around,
we're barely making it.
I'm not working for him.
Now, pack.
BRUCE: Detective Gordon.
Bruce.
I didn't hear you.
What happened?
Ah. Nothing. Harvey and
I were tracking a gang.
We let ourselves get surprised.
What brings you down here?
I found this when
I was in the city.
Wasn't sure what to do with it.
One of Penguin's licenses.
Apparently, crime is legal now.
And you're going
along with that?
Not really.
There's a number on the license.
I was thinking Penguin must
have some sort of master list.
Connecting the crime and
the criminal to the license issue.
List like that would tell you not
only who committed that crime,
but crimes that haven't
even happened yet.
Unfortunately, the judges
are going along
with the licenses,
and trying to track down
who in Penguin's
organization keeps the list
would set off too many alarms.
I see.
But you haven't given up.
You just said you were
out tracking a gang.
It's different.
This gang isn't licensed.
But Penguin will come after
them, if he hasn't already,
and when he catches them,
it'll be more proof that
Gotham doesn't need the GCPD.
Sorry, it's been a long day.
So, why not use Penguin
to lead you to them?
If I could figure out
how to do that, I would.
It was good to
see you, Detective.
You should come by
the house for dinner.
Yes.
I'd like that.
How about we grab a bite...
Tonight.
Exclusive but welcoming.
Urbane and edgy.
Tonight's opening
will establish the
Iceberg Lounge
as Gotham's newest place to see,
and be seen.
And you say you acquired
the club from Barbara Kean?
Is that a question?
It's just no one's seen
her for months, and...
Barbara Kean's whereabouts
are not my concern.
This was The Sirens
club. It is now mine.
MAN: Mr. Cobblepot,
there's a rumor going around
about criminals being given licenses.
The rumor is
you're issuing them.
Tell me, what is the
crime rate in Gotham?
We're at historic lows.
Historic lows...
You know, Augustus
Caesar once presided
over the longest period of peace and
prosperity the world has ever known.
It was called the Pax Romana.
Perhaps one day, this will be
known as the Pax Penguina.
That's not a denial.
We're here to
talk about my club.
Your readers will find
this interesting. Ivy?
(REMOTE BEEPS)
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
That's Edward Nygma.
Turns out, Ed had a
very rare brain disease,
and there was only one option,
to freeze him and
wait for the cure.
In his final lucid moments,
he begged me, "Oswald,
do not hide me away.
"Put me out with the people."
It was the least I could do.
Anyone tell him he
was being frozen?
I have affidavits from his doctor
if you would like to see them.
No, thanks.
Well, Jim.
I'm rather busy, so
whatever your business is...
I came to tell
you you're a fraud.
The gang that has
Crane's fear toxin,
they're not afraid of you.
Others will find out.
That's how it begins.
You've had a nice run,
Oswald, but it's over.
Oh, Jim, it's so hard to admit
when you've become irrelevant.
Let me tell you
what's gonna happen.
I'm going to find this gang
and I'm going to crush them.
And everyone will see
that it is Oswald Cobblepot,
the Penguin, who
keeps Gotham safe.
Always good to
see you, old friend.
As he prepares for the
opening of the Iceberg Lounge,
Oswald Cobblepot announced
that he would destroy the gang
that attacked Gotham First
National Bank yesterday.
He described them as
cowards and pond scum.
(SIGHS)
Penguin's goin' down tonight.
- You finish that new batch yet?
- Yes.
Now, can you please... Can
you please get rid of that, please?
- What, you and him ain't gettin' along?
- Please, just get rid of it.
Listen, I got to do
some things tonight,
but I think you guys should
spend some time together. Huh?
We all have our fears to face.
(WHIMPERING)
Stop! Stop! Please, stop!
Please! No!
Stop!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Let me out!
Remember how you accused me
of being a slave to my emotions?
No more.
I have banished those feelings.
And look how I have risen.
But at what cost?
I wonder which of us is frozen.
Him.
He's, like, totally frozen.
Ivy, go somewhere else.
All right,
I want two unmarked
units at street level
and another two teams with me and
Harvey watching the entrances to the club.
The moment that
gang arrives, we move.
You heard the
man! Suit up, let's go!
Can we count on them?
Let's see. You tricked Penguin
into baiting the gang to attack his club
hoping to arrest them
before they cause mass panic
only so you could embarrass Penguin.
So I would say, yeah, they're about as
dependable as any other
part of this cockamamie plan.
Thanks, I'll get the gas masks.
Please, let me out!
SCARECROW: Jonathan.
Let me out!
SCARECROW: Jonathan!
(ROARING)
- So, you guys work for Penguin, huh?
- It ain't like that.
- Sure.
- Come on, Gordon.
Since Penguin's been
cracking down, life's been good.
Why you gotta rock the boat?
What happens when he starts
giving out licenses for murders?
Huh? What then?
- I'm wasting my breath, aren't I?
- Pretty much.
All right, then.
Who wants it first?
(JAZZY MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Mr. Wayne. Mr. Pennyworth.
- I am so glad you could make it.
- It's our pleasure.
Congratulations.
We were just admiring
your frozen mate.
Is he still alive in there?
I fear we may never know.
But you'll know when
you finally thaw him out,
when they discover
a cure for his disease.
Oh, yes, then, of course.
I wanted to personally thank you
for everything you've
done for this city.
Thank you, Mr. Wayne.
So...
Can I ask about the licenses?
A little discretion, if you
would, Master Bruce?
Everybody's talking
about it, Alfred,
I just want to
know how it works.
So, does someone
come to you and say,
"I want to rob a bank"?
Now, Bruce, if I
didn't know any better,
I would think that you
wanted me to implicate myself.
Anything you say
stays between us.
First, let me ask,
you would be agreeable to
the idea of licensed crime?
If crime had been licensed
and controlled three years ago,
my parents would still be alive.
Exactly so.
Well, between us,
I have nothing to do
with the licenses directly.
I provide the guidelines
while Mr. Penn
handles all of the details.
Now, would you excuse me?
- Well done, sir.
- Thank you.
Now we know who has the list.
The next step is...
Selina.
Where's your babysitter?
It's kind of a package deal.
Yeah, well, he's got me.
Is that good enough or not?
Actually, we're both in.
- I should pat you down for weapons.
- Sure.
- If you wanna lose a hand.
- It was worth a shot.
I'll tell the boss.
See ya.
You were worried about me.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey, man, I've been
looking all over for you.
Ooh, ouch.
Think we can
forget about backup.
I see you talked to some
of your fellow officers.
- Probably not a bad thing.
- How's that?
Guys get to let off steam,
resentments don't fester.
Next time, you can
get punched in the face.
This beautiful mug,
no one would dare.
Let's go.
All right, once inside, get
Zsasz and Penguin first,
and then go crazy.
I still don't see Penguin.
PENGUIN: Hello!
I'm guessing that gas isn't faster
than a bullet, what do you think?
Jim Gordon and his
ham-fisted manipulation.
He thought he fooled me.
You wanna do 'em
here or downstairs?
- Might be a little loud in here.
- Neither.
I have something
special planned for them.
What do you want, Bruce?
You knew I'd follow you.
Just like I knew
you'd come up here.
You don't know
anything about me.
I wanted to apologize for
what I said at the hospital
when you came to visit Alfred.
You were making a kind gesture.
You wanna talk to
me, come up here.
My point is, I'm sorry.
Yeah, you were a jerk.
I saw you arrive
with Tabitha Galavan.
I'm not sure I'd
choose her as a mentor.
Wow.
That means absolutely
nothing to me.
Selina...
Oh?
You wanna say something?
It's a lovely dress
you're wearing tonight.
(APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS)
Honestly, you two,
why can't you just go to the
cinema like normal teenagers?
And, Master Bruce, we got a
bit of a situation downstairs, sir.
What sort of situation?
Ms. Kyle.
PENGUIN: For the past three
months, I have given this city
a tranquility it
has never known.
Now, I would like to ensure
that peace for the future.
In the weeks to come,
you will hear whispers
about what's happening
on the streets of Gotham.
All you need to know is
without me, this
is what you get.
Men who want to bring
fear back to our city.
Who promise a
return to the old days.
So, tell your families,
tell your friends,
it is Oswald Cobblepot
who keeps them safe.
Not the GCPD.
You're welcome.
I have my things in the car, we
can stop them in the parking garage.
Absolutely not, Master Bruce.
Alfred, Penguin's gonna take
those men out and kill them.
Undoubtedly so.
But, as you said before,
you can make a difference.
There is time for masks, and
there is a time for Bruce Wayne.
PENGUIN: Do you know
what's going to be done to you?
Wait!
I want to know what you're
gonna do with those men.
You need not concern
yourself with that.
Are those men going to
be turned over to the police?
(CHUCKLES)
Earlier tonight, you thanked
me for making the city safer.
Now, how do you
think that happened?
I do the dirty work
no one else will.
I understand.
But I'm asking you, turn
those men over to the police.
You're young.
You have a good heart.
No.
Enjoy your party, Penguin.
You little twerp.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
- (GUN COCKING)
- (GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(DISTORTED) What's wrong?
You scared?
(SCREAMING)
(DISTORTED LAUGHTER)
(GRUNTING)
No!
(LAUGHING)
GORDON: Hey!
(THUDS)
You're under arrest.
By order of the Gotham City
Police Department. Cuff him.
(PENGUIN GASPS)
(GASPING)
Help me. Help me.
(SOBBING)
HARVEY: Penguin
ain't gonna be too happy.
Screw him.
I'm just worried about
finding Jonathan Crane.
If he's out there with access
to his father's formula...
Relax, we'll find him.
Wouldn't expect too much
help from these parts, though.
There's good cops out there.
They just need reminding.
(CARS HONKING)
BRUCE: You have a list
of all the licenses
you've given. I want it.
I... I can't.
Penguin, he'll...
(GASPS)
(EXHALES SHAKILY)
(GLASS SHATTERS IN DISTANCE)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
(ALARM RINGING)
MAN 1: What about the
alarm? MAN 2: Forget it.
We got a license, remember?
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(GLASS CRACKLING)
Oh, no.
What the...
(DOOR CRASHES)
OFFICER: GCPD.
Gotham Police,
you're under arrest.
Crane, you got to make
more of that fear gas.
We got to get
Merton out of jail.
Crane!
Crane?
(DISTORTED) Jonathan
Crane isn't here anymore.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
It's just the Scarecrow.
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
English - SDH